<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pingshan Art Musuem</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Pingshan Art Musuem</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/program/fourseason-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/program/fourseason-01/</guid>
      <description>Four Seasons Salon, an academic salon initiated and hosted by the Pingsan Art Museum and co-curated by Da Bian Lu, an art media platform, is a recurring event throughout four seasons.
 + Read More The inaugural salon, held in October 2019, established a live scene of dialogue between architecture and contemporary art, opening multiple interfaces of local cultural understanding. Four Seasons sets itself apart from lectures and thematic academic forums, with &amp;ldquo;Dialogue&amp;rdquo; being a key feature, putting conversations at the forefront.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/program/unknowncity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/program/unknowncity/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Unknown City: Installation and Imagery on Chinese Contemporary Architecture&amp;rdquo; is the first exhibition at Pingshan Art Museum (PAM), joined by numerous practitioners related to the field of architecture in China&amp;rsquo;s 40 years of rapid urbanization. During the time, the architects designed the city themselves, but were also &amp;ldquo;bewildered&amp;rdquo; by the city, as the urban space became ever uncertain and complex. This paradoxical cycle of material creation and cultural disintegration undoubtedly has deep philosophical connotations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/program/artcamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/program/artcamp/</guid>
      <description>For two weeks, nearly 15 groups of artists/groups are stationed in Pingshan to create live artworks, inviting the public to interact with the arts. The theme, &amp;ldquo;Chirp - Art Camping&amp;rdquo; for exchanges and communication, is inspired by the lifestyle of young people in the south, such as camping, music and film festivals in a warm climate.
 + Read More Pingshan Art Museum&amp;rsquo;s deputy director Li Yao, has taken art out of the museum&amp;rsquo;s architectural box and brought it into public and outdoor spaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/program/synchronicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/program/synchronicity/</guid>
      <description>Coined synchronicity by the Swiss psychologist Carl Gustav Jung (1875-1961), contemplations on meaningful coincidences and timelessness are reflected upon at Synchronicity, the first contemporary art exhibition of Pingshan Art Museum (PAM). The structure of the exhibition echoes the title presented in a parallel relationship. Curator LI Zhenhua described the exhibition as &amp;ldquo;seven personal stories in flashback&amp;rdquo;, which connects the creative logic of the seven artists in their own language, geography and intellectual experience of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/program/anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/program/anniversary/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;No one would have imagined that the Pingshan Art Museum would mark the first anniversary of its new establishment on this bleak March day. It&amp;rsquo;s a moment to remember. Each person, each institution, is trying to adjust itself toward the summer of unknown and hope. We stand at this waypoint, looking back, looking forward. We record, contemplate, imagine and celebrate with art. Life goes on, art accompanies, and we appreciate the attention and help of friends in the past year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/program/muse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/program/muse/</guid>
      <description>In 2019, the Pingshan Art Museum presented the annual exhibition Synchronicity, from the curator&amp;rsquo;s beautiful vision of spending time together in harmony to the New Year, the current situation unexpectedly gives rise to another meaning of &amp;ldquo;synchronicity&amp;rdquo; - &amp;ldquo;spending difficult times together&amp;rdquo;. The epidemic has changed a lot and the future trajectory remains unclear. What should we and our museums do in the midst of this? Art may seem feeble at the moment, but its true power lies in the process of recording, experiencing and reflecting on things that give us a wake-up call, thus giving us hope for the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/program/pagoda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/program/pagoda/</guid>
      <description>Nine-Tiered Pagoda: Spatial and Visual Magic, as a cross-disciplinary event, represents an unprecedented direction and form of exhibition in China. Nine (groups of) artists will provide their works as the basis material for the exhibition. Besides, nine architects and nine designers will also join to form nine temporary teams, hence the cooperation among artists, architects and designers. There is no ‘priority’ or ‘center’ in the exhibition, only division of labor and collaboration, presenting nine individual exhibitions of a brand-new type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about PAM</title>
      <link>/about/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/intro/</guid>
      <description>The Pingshan Art Museum (PAM) is situated in Shenzhen Pingshan Culture Quarter, with a total area of 9,900 square meters. With an open-ended approach for artistic exploration, PAM is concerned about the cross-boundaries integration and fission of a range of areas. That include technology, media, environment in the changing society of the times. By putting forward different forms and expressions in space, PAM preserves, collects and disseminates the vitality and vision of art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>architecture</title>
      <link>/about/architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/architecture/</guid>
      <description>The architecture was commissioned in 2014 and designed by renowned Chinese architect DONG Gong. Part of the building&amp;rsquo;s ground floor is elevated, its design intersperses different functions within the edifice. This allows certain operations to remain as active urban spaces that draw people through even after the museum is closed. The design of PAM not only serves functionally as a temple of art, but also a space that provides serenity in the union of art, spirit and city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>art community from contemporary to vernacular</title>
      <link>/about/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/community/</guid>
      <description>The latest Pingshan Art Museum is an addition to the Pingshan Art Cluster, which consists of the PAM (current expansion), the old Pingshan Art Museum, Pingshan Sculpture Creative Park, Dawan Shiju, and Golden Turtle Nature Study Room. These art spaces of diverse orientation, attract local and international artists and audiences to promote artistic interaction, collaboration and development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>culture quarter</title>
      <link>/about/cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/cluster/</guid>
      <description>Pingshan Culture Quarter is a major public cultural infrastructure in Shenzhen, a project of Pingshan District to create a cultural high ground to the east of the city. It aims to advance cultural development, promote cultural benefits to people and improve the functional quality of the city. This new cultural landmark is made up of a theater, library, art museum, exhibition hall, cultural and creative experience hall, conference center, book city, cinema and other venues, integrating performances, readings, public art exhibitions, arts experiences, conferences and other cultural functions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
