<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>exhibition on Pingshan Art Musuem</title>
    <link>/categories/exhibition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in exhibition on Pingshan Art Musuem</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/categories/exhibition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/program/unknowncity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/program/unknowncity/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Unknown City: Installation and Imagery on Chinese Contemporary Architecture&amp;rdquo; is the first exhibition at Pingshan Art Museum (PAM), joined by numerous practitioners related to the field of architecture in China&amp;rsquo;s 40 years of rapid urbanization. During the time, the architects designed the city themselves, but were also &amp;ldquo;bewildered&amp;rdquo; by the city, as the urban space became ever uncertain and complex. This paradoxical cycle of material creation and cultural disintegration undoubtedly has deep philosophical connotations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/program/synchronicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/program/synchronicity/</guid>
      <description>Coined synchronicity by the Swiss psychologist Carl Gustav Jung (1875-1961), contemplations on meaningful coincidences and timelessness are reflected upon at Synchronicity, the first contemporary art exhibition of Pingshan Art Museum (PAM). The structure of the exhibition echoes the title presented in a parallel relationship. Curator LI Zhenhua described the exhibition as &amp;ldquo;seven personal stories in flashback&amp;rdquo;, which connects the creative logic of the seven artists in their own language, geography and intellectual experience of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/program/muse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/program/muse/</guid>
      <description>In 2019, the Pingshan Art Museum presented the annual exhibition Synchronicity, from the curator&amp;rsquo;s beautiful vision of spending time together in harmony to the New Year, the current situation unexpectedly gives rise to another meaning of &amp;ldquo;synchronicity&amp;rdquo; - &amp;ldquo;spending difficult times together&amp;rdquo;. The epidemic has changed a lot and the future trajectory remains unclear. What should we and our museums do in the midst of this? Art may seem feeble at the moment, but its true power lies in the process of recording, experiencing and reflecting on things that give us a wake-up call, thus giving us hope for the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/program/pagoda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/program/pagoda/</guid>
      <description>Nine-Tiered Pagoda: Spatial and Visual Magic, as a cross-disciplinary event, represents an unprecedented direction and form of exhibition in China. Nine (groups of) artists will provide their works as the basis material for the exhibition. Besides, nine architects and nine designers will also join to form nine temporary teams, hence the cooperation among artists, architects and designers. There is no ‘priority’ or ‘center’ in the exhibition, only division of labor and collaboration, presenting nine individual exhibitions of a brand-new type.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
